The big ones were waterboarding, the
cold cell, and sleep deprivation. And
and the Justice Department never said
anything about that. They're like, "Oh,
listen. Uh, you know, you can do these
techniques, and if you kill him, just
bury him out back." Nah, that wasn't the
that wasn't the approved operation.
>> Was any of it effective? Like, was there
any actionable information?
>> That's that's the worst part of this. It
it No, none of it was effective.
Joe Rogan and John Kiryahu just exposed
the dark truth about CIA torture
programs, whether they were effective,
what kind of torture was used in
contravention of the US Constitution by
our criminal government, and what this
means for American policy. Kiryaku is a
former CIA official who is a
whistleblower that blew the lid off CIA
atrocities during the Bush and Cheney
terms. So, let's get his take on this.
Please like the video and subscribe to
the channel.
>> They worked with L with LSD for 20 years
at least at least 20 years. You know,
they there was an operation, it was a
sub operation of MK Ultra
>> where um they rented a safe house in San
Francisco. They recruited a bunch of
hookers and had them go out and pick up
John's, bring them back to the to the
safe house where they thought they were
going to get laid, dose them with LSD,
and then interrogate them and try to get
them to give up their deepest secrets.
>> It's like Midnight Climax.
>> Yeah. Midnight climax. Exactly. It's
like, what? Nobody's agreed to do this.
You You haven't informed them properly.
These are American citizens. You can't
just take people off the streets and and
force LSD down there.
>> Well, they were running the hate
ashberry free clinic. Yeah.
>> Until right after a month after Chaos by
Tom O'Neal came out. Yeah,
>> you're exactly right.
>> Yeah. Yeah. My mom my uh wife's mom went
there.
>> She used to She was a hippie in San
Francisco. She went to the Hate Ashbury
Free Clinic.
>> It was run by the CIA, which is so
crazy. And it's totally connected to
Manson and the man.
>> Oh yeah. Mansa. Exactly. Exactly. Manson
was a part of it as well.
>> It's so nuts. And they wouldn't have
even known about that until they found a
stash of documents that connected it all
together.
>> Yeah. And a lot of the MK Ultra
documents were shredded by the CIA. We
know that after the Church Committee,
that's what happened. And this was their
excuse to conduct torture on Americans
that, you know, we just need this
information so bad that we can just
subvert due process. And then several
decades later, they're saying, "Well,
these are just terrorists. We can
torture them under CIA black sites, and
you know that that will get around these
constitutional limitations, which is an
implicit way of saying, hey, the
Constitution prohibits this garbage, by
the way." And this is just what we put
up with from our modern deep state, from
our modern CIA. No heads essentially
rolled over this. There are a few court
decisions in federal courts that, you
know, reversed kind of the Bush era
strategy for these torture techniques,
but at the same time, no one had to pay
the price. These were vile crimes that
none of us would get away with, but
somehow our government gets away with
because there's a double standard for
government.
>> And just think of what's been destroyed,
>> right?
>> What we could have learned.
>> Exactly. We only know a small fraction
of what was done. So, is it a case of
just they're they're not elected,
they're put into power, presidents come
and go, and over the course of their
career, 20 years plus, they just have so
much power and so much ability to get
things done that they just bypass the
law.
>> I I think that is that's the whole story
right there in a nutshell. When I was
there, I remember being shocked by some
of the old-timers who had been there for
as long as 40 or 42 years. There was one
in particular. He was the national
intelligence officer for warning. So he
was the one that was supposed to say,
you know, I'm worried about what Libya
is going to look like 10 years from now
and then somebody writes a paper about
it. He had been there for 42 years. He
had to get a a waiver from the director
because he had aged out. Well, these
guys make no secret of of their belief
that they can outweight pretty much any
president. Presidents come and go and
these guys are there forever. And so if
the president wants him to do something
that they don't want to do, they just
slow roll it. Just wait until he leaves.
>> Yeah. Doesn't that say something about
the deep state in general? how much
continuity there is in these bureaucrats
and the power they wield and the ideas
that they hold that they can just wait
for a president that is a little more
amendable to what they want to do to get
in power to actually unleash these
crimes if it's more controversial
relative to one president than to
another. No matter we can just outlast
that president. But it's also too bad
that most presidents have been complicit
with this nonsense. Certainly Bush and
Obama were and you know you see this
rhetoric of applying those same
standards that they said you know would
just apply to terrorists but applied
inward to the United States where hey if
you're a dissident you're a terrorist
you know the war on terror has been
focused inward and it's been focused
inward on a lot of the right you know
they were insurrectionists on January
6th they told us right and you know we
had to do something for it we had to
throw the book at those people. More,
you know, jail time toward those people
than the criminals that killed, you
know, 5 million people overseas in the
federal government under the war on
terror in general. That's what we get.
We get inwardfacing
governmental coercion on these things
that we're told at first will protect
us. No, they will not protect us. They
will be a sword against our throat in
the future for future presidents.
>> And that's the end of it. You know,
that's why I say I I've said this in
interviews a lot. There is a deep state.
You don't have to call it the deep state
if you don't want to. You can call it
the state. You can call it the federal
bureaucracy. You can call it whatever
you want. The fact is it exists and it's
unelected and it's generally
unaccountable to anybody and they just
wait for the president to leave if they
don't want to do what he wants.
>> So, you find out about this torture
program. you won't participate. So that
puts you on the outs. And when do you
know that this is going to be like a
significant problem in your career?
>> You know, honestly, I didn't know until
well after I left the agency. You know,
once I I turned this down
um and I got this outofcycle promotion
for the Abu Beta operation, I was I was
named executive assistant to the CIA's
deputy director for operations. And in
that position, you have access to
literally everything that the CIA is
doing around the world. And so I'm
reading these cables coming back from
the secret site and people are saying
like, "Whoa, I didn't sign up for this.
Nobody said we're going to torture
people. I quit." And then they come
home. Or there was a secretary who
fainted once when she happened to be in
the room while Abu Zubeda was being
tortured. and she curtailed her her
assignment. That means she sends a cable
to headquarters saying, "I'm coming
home. I'm not doing this anymore." That
is a careerending decision to curtail an
assignment. And I remember thinking,
"So, I'm not the only one who thinks
this is this is illegal. Certainly,
somebody's going to come out and say
something." And nobody did.
>> Like, what are the techniques that they
were using that were like causing her to
faint?
The big ones were waterboarding, the
cold cell, and sleep deprivation. Sleep
deprivation doesn't sound like any big
deal. And when that finally leaked, Don
Rumsfeld, who was the Secretary of
Defense at the time, made a statement
that that still kind of sticks in my
mind. He said, "There is no such thing
as sleep deprivation." He said, "I have
a standup desk in my office. I don't
even have a chair in my office and
sometimes I'll work 24 hours and then
into the next day 36 hours. But that's
not what we're talking about here. We
know Yeah, that's not what we're talking
about. He can eat his Cheetos, eat
whatever food he wants, leaves and go as
he chooses. There's literally no
comparison to being held under sleep
deprivation under a CIA interrogation at
a at a black site. And a black site
means, you know, one of the sites in
Syria and Egypt. I think the Bush
administration even at one point had to
acknowledge their existence once
information of this leaked out that they
were taking, you know, high prize
terrorist interrogation targets to these
sites to do this. And these aren't only
the only few techniques as we'll talk
about in a second, but it's totally vile
vile that this was, you know, said by a
secretary of defense when the
constitution that they're claiming to be
champions of, hey, we believe in the
constitution and limited government.
We're the conservative majority now when
the neocons were in power. Well, guess
what? That prohibits cruel and unusual
punishment. That's exactly what the CIA
did. Something we couldn't do. There's
no way American citizens could delegate
that power to our government cuz we
ourselves don't hold that power.
Thankfully so. Because we know it's
morally wrong when the government does
it. I hate to say, well, I love to say
actually, it's also morally wrong. Know
from the American Psychological
Association that people begin to lose
their minds at day seven with no sleep
and they begin to die. Their organs
begin to shut down at day nine. But the
CIA was authorized to keep people awake
for 12 days. And that was another thing
that caused prisoners to just die. They
would have heart failure. You know,
>> how' they keep them awake?
>> You chain them to that eyebolt in the
ceiling again. You have these industrial
strength lights on them 24 hours a day
and like death metal 24 hours on volume
11. And um and they just can't sleep
because if they if they collapse,
they'll pull their arms out of their
sockets. They're chained to that to that
eyebolt.
>> Jeez,
>> it was bad. And then when people would
die,
they would just dig a hole next to the
interrogation building, put them in the
hole, cover it up, and then bring the
next guy in.
>> No questions asked. You think that got a
lot of mainstream news coverage? Not
exactly. Even when, you know, a lot of
the mainstream news was supposed to be
against the Bush administration, never
was against the war on terror, never was
really against the war in Iraq. You
know, cheerleled for that, including
Judith Miller at the New York Times.
This stuff was just buried under a rug
where it sat and it never came back to
haunt these people and perpetrators
involved. No, no crime. Going down for
no crimes, no heads rolled over this
stuff. It's just so putrid and such a
vile part of the American deep state
that it's impossible to avoid if you dig
into this stuff. It will leave you jaded
about the American political system in
general. Knowing how much, you know, our
political overseers tout how great the
United States is, you know, and the our
government, how it's so different and,
you know, more valuable and more, you
know, just than any other government in
the world, yet it does these sorts of
things.
No report, no nothing,
>> nothing. There was one guy they reported
on and and headquarters wrote back and
said, "Just put him on ice until we can
figure out what to do." And they let
literally just put him in a bathtub and
filled it with ice and then just decided
a couple days later he started to turn.
We should probably bury this guy.
>> Wow.
>> Yeah, it was ugly. And and the Justice
Department never said anything about
that. They're like, "Oh, listen. Uh you
know, you can do these techniques and if
you kill him, just bury him out back."
Yeah, that wasn't the that wasn't the
approved operation.
>> Was any of it effective? Like, was there
any actionable information?
>> That's that's the worst part of this. It
it No, none of it was effective.
>> Yeah, man. This is just gruesome and
vile. It is some of the worst things
that the government has engaged in
during my lifetime. It's so glad I'm so
glad to hear John Kiryaku of all people
talk about it. He's a literal hero for
exposing this stuff from inside the CIA.
At great risk to himself, by the way, so
protect him at all costs. But he also
needs a pardon. He needs a pardon for
the same reason that Julian Assange and
Edward Snowden do for unmasking the
evils of the state that play out. And
when you do that, when you're
transparent with the public, you about
crimes that have been committed, that is
no crime whatsoever. He deserves medals
and immediate pardon right now. Do I
think that's going to happen? No, I
don't think that's going to happen
because a lot of those tools on the war
on terror is something that governments
regardless of who the president is at
the time cling to for their own
protections and to sell as protecting
the American public. But just I mean
just look at this. This is just vile.
Andrew Npalitano had an article last
year about how during the trial of
Khaled Shake Muhammad who which is still
going on. He was one of the architects
of 9/11, probably the primary architect
of 9/11 essentially within al-Qaeda.
They're talking about the witnesses they
have for the government. And the
government's trying to claim that a lot
of the terrorist revelations uh that
were given were done voluntarily
despite, you know, acknowledging a lot
of this torture that happened and things
that happened at these CIA black sites
were just so horrific. You know, some of
these people were raped in in ways that
I won't even describe on this video.
It's that's this is in addition to the
water boarding and cold cell and sleep
deprivation. And Andrew Npalitano was
talking about how the government can't
even maintain its case when they have
some witnesses like basically telling
the truth, letting the mass slip a
little bit about what actually happened,
including one that, you know, was on
record saying that he would slit the
throat of the son of one of these
terrorists they were torturing. It's
just so horrific. I mean, I I think what
he says here is just so clairvoyant and
so true. The Bush Cheney torture regime
and its Devil's Island at GMO are among
the darkest events perpetrated by a
modern American presidency. So true. But
that's not it. I mean, in 2014, we
actually got a a Senate Intelligence
Committee report about torture that was
perpetrated by the Bush administration.
This is the Washington Post. It's
essentially a neocon rag. But even it
built this site to show how horrific and
atrocious and heinous these crimes were.
And you can just click on these
individual things that they put in the
document and how it's clarified. Number
one, it wasn't even an effective means
of acquiring intelligence that was borne
out in this document by the Senate. By
the way, it rested on inaccurate claims
of their effectiveness. like they had
drumed up this, you know, campaign to
claim that this was effective techniques
to extract real information, but it
really wasn't. It was brutal and far
worse than the CIA represented,
especially in public. You can read about
that, too. It impeded White House
oversight, as if the White House really
wanted oversight over this, by the way.
Bush totally was complicit, but that's
what they claim in this report.
You know, deeply flawed throughout the
program's duration. All these things,
you know, just spell disaster. These
would not be appropriate defenses. If we
were caught in these acts, if we
tortured another person by sleep
deprivation or or raped them or, you
know, cold cell or waterboarding, we'd
be put behind bars for a long time.
Doesn't happen when it comes to the
government. They get out of the
scot-free. But like I said, John Kiyaku,
just a chilling podcast in general with
Joe Rogan. really awesome podcast in
general to listen to. If you listen to
the entire thing, I highly recommend it.
The original link is in the description.
And I think he's just a hero in my mind.
I will listen to anything that man says.
The man's honest. He said things that
were at great risk to his own reputation
and life, spending, you know, years in
jail for this, I believe. And, you know,
that's just the truth. CIA torture is a
real thing. It's a real thing to grapple
with and it's just another reason why
the CIA must be abolished. You can't
reform that monster. You can't put John
Ratcliffe at the head of the CIA and
just say, "Oh, hey, everything's good
now. Everything's reformed." You can't
name Tulsi Gabbard the director of
national intelligence and be like, "All
right, well, the CIA's turned, you know,
turned a new page in its history and now
it's a good force for protecting
Americans." It's not. Regardless of what
you think of Tulsi Gabbard or John
Ratcliffe, the latter is especially
vile. He was, you know, the architect of
expanding FISA 702 while in Congress, by
the way. You can read up on that if you
want. But I'm glad for this podcast.
Thank you for shedding light on this,
John. Thanks, Rogan, for having him on.
What do you think about this? What does
this say about the CIA? Does it just
need to be abolished? Do heads need to
roll? Will this behavior continue if
heads don't roll? Let me know in the
comments down below. Like the video,
subscribe to the channel. Also,
subscribe to Joe Rogan. Thanks, Joe, for
this interview. And if you like my video
and my commentary, please consider
becoming a YouTube member if you click
the join button below. You can help
support my channel. I will graciously
appreciate that if you do. And in return
for that deed, I will give you access to
all my videos before they go live to the
general public on YouTube. And until I
see you guys next time, no more war, no
more debt, no more inflation, and no
more empire. Peace out, guys. Catch you
in the next one.